Finding Aid for Medical School (University of Michigan) records, 1850-2010
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
- Audio-Visual Materials
  - Photographs (Box 136)
    - General Files
      - Medical Center Administration (John Forsyth, Joseph Johnson, George Zuidema, Rhetaugh Dumas) (prints) (Box 136)
      - Nurses and Nursing (prints) (Box 136)
      - Staff (Box 136)
      - Survival Flight (helicopter), ca. 1986, print (Box 136)
      - University Hospital (interiors & exteriors) 1986, undated, prints (Box 136)
    - Classes by Subject
      - Histology Classes, 3 items including 1 Gibson print (Box 136)
      - Surgery and Anatomy Classes
        - Amphitheater Views, Dissections, including 4 Gibson prints; 6 items (Box 136)
        - Groups, formal, including 3 Gibson prints; 5 items (Box 136)
        - Groups, informal, including 3 Gibson prints; 5 items (Box 136)
    - Classes by Years
      - 1872 (Box 136)
      - 1880 (Box 136)
      - 1883 (Box 136)
      - 1885 (Box 136)
      - 1891 (Box 136)
      - 1901 (Box 136)
      - 1918 (Box 136)
      - 1919 (Box 136)
      - 1925 (Box 136)
      - 1952 (Box 136)
      - 1953 (Box 136)
      - 1954 (Box 136)
      - 1955 (Box 136)
      - 1956 (Box 136)
      - 1957 (Box 136)
      - 1958 (Box 136)
      - 1959 (Box 136)
      - 1960 (Box 136)
      - 1961 (Box 136)
      - 1962 (Box 136)
      - 1963 (Box 136)
      - 1964 (Box 136)
      - 1965 (Box 136)
      - 1966 (Box 136)
      - 1967 (Box 136)
      - 1968 (Box 136)
      - 1969 (Box 136)
      - 1970 (Box 136)
      - 1971 (Box 136)
      - 1972 (Box 136)
      - 1973 (Box 136)
      - 1974 (Box 136)
      - 1975 (Box 136)
      - 1976 (Box 136)
      - 1977 (Box 136)
      - 1978 (Box 136)
    - Class Nights (by Years)
      - 1963 or 1964 (Box 136)
      - 1967 (Box 136)
      - 1969 (Box 136)
  - Negatives
    - negatives of class photos (Box 136)
  - Films
    - University Hospital buildings and construction, 6 film reels 16 mm (Box 136)
    - Medical Alumni Conference 89th Annual Open Exercises 1983, 1 film reels 16 mm (Box 136)
  - Outsize Photographs
    - Faculty (Folder Bimu/C41)
    - Classes by years
      - Unidentified year (Folder UBImu/C46)
      - 1863 (Folder UBImu/C46)
      - 1870-1871 (Folder UBImu/C46)
      - 1874 (Folder UBImu/C46)
      - 1879 (Folder UBImu/C46)
      - 1881 (Folder UBImu/C46)
      - 1882 (Folder UBImu/C46)
      - 1883 (Folder UBImu/C46)
      - 1884 (Folder UBImu/C46)
      - 1885 (Folder UBImu/C46)
      - 1887 (Folder UBImu/C46)
      - 1889 (Folder UBImu/C46)
      - 1890 (Folder UBImu/C46)
      - 1891 (Folder UBImu/C46)
      - 1892 (Folder UBImu/C46)
      - 1893 (Folder UBImu/C46)
      - 1894 (Folder UBImu/C46)
        (large and medium)
      - 1895 (Folder UBImu/C46)
      - 1897 (Folder UBImu/C46)
      - 1898 (Folder UBImu/C46)
      - 1899 (Folder UBImu/C46)
      - 1901 (Folder UBImu/C46)
      - 1902 (Folder UBImu/C46)
      - 1903 (Folder UBImu/C46)
      - 1905 (Folder UBImu/C46)
      - ca. 1905 (Folder UBImu/C46)
      - 1911 (Folder UBImu/C46)
      - 1912-1913 (Folder UBImu/C46)
      - 1927 (Folder UBImu/C46)
      - 1929 (Folder UBImu/C46)
      - 1932 (Folder UBImu/C46)
      - 1969 (Folder UBImu/C46)
    - Gibson Photographs (Folder UBImu/C46)
  - Drawings
    - Drawing of 1903 Medical Building 1946, 1 folders (Folder UBImu/C46)
  - Photographs: STAFF USE ONLY (Researchers must use photocopies in Box 136)
    - General Files
      - Faculty (from album of 1918) (Box 213)
      - Faculty-Group Photos (Box 213)
      - Faculty-Individuals (Box 213)
      - Gibson Photographs 1893, 4 folders (Box 213)
      - Gibson Glass Plate Negative (Fragile) (Box 213)
      - Life Magazine Photos (Box 213)
    - Staff (Box 213)
    - Classes by Subject
      - Histology Classes (Box 213)
      - Surgery and Anatomy Classes
        - Amphitheater Views (Box 213)
        - Dissections (Box 213)
        - Groups, formal (Box 213)
        - Groups, informal (Box 213)
    - Classes by Years
      - 1872 (Box 213)
      - 1880 (Box 213)
      - 1883 (Box 213)
      - 1885 (Box 213)
      - 1891 (Box 213)
      - 1901 (Box 213)
      - 1918 (Box 213)
      - 1919 (Box 213)
      - 1925 (Box 213)
- Archived Website
  The Archived Medical School Website documents the academic programs, accomplishments, resources, events, and people at the School. Content includes important news and announcements, publications (such as newsletters and course catalogs), and information about admissions, curriculum, degree requirements, faculty, and the overall mission of the School. Starting in 2010, this archived website will be captured on a regular, ongoing basis as part of the University of Michigan Web Archives, hosted at http://webarchives.cdlib.org/a/universityofmichigan/.
  - Medical School
    - 1997-[ONGOING]
      (These versions were preserved by the Internet Archive and are made available through its Wayback Machine. The Bentley Historical Library is not involved in the collection or maintenance of this material.)
    - May 16, 2002, .ZIP file
    - June 23, 2003, .ZIP file
    - May 19-20, 2008, .ZIP file
    - 2010-[ONGOING]
  - Related Resources: Curricula, Degree Requirements, Policies, Research Initiatives, Centers, and Institutes
    - April 17, 2007, .ZIP file
    - 2010-[ONGOING]
Index to Major Subjects
The locations specified for the various added and subject entries are not necessarily the only locations within the collection where material on the specified subject will be found. In particular, important matters are often discussed in the Executive Committee minutes or the Dean's Advisory Council minutes. Neither of these are indexed here.
Partial Index to Correspondence
Academic Freedom (Loyalty investigation of Mark Nickerson, 1954)
(box 57)
Affiliated Hospitals
(boxes 30, 94, 102, 105, 107, 157, 165, 192, 286-289)
Grand Rapids Area Medical Education Center
(boxes 4, 102, 171)
Henry Ford Hospital
(boxes 94, 102, 126, 171, 178, 214, 227)
St. Joseph Mercy Hospital
(boxes 94, 102-103, 108, 111, 127, 177, 195, 233)
Veterans Administration Hospital
(boxes 5, 16, 86, 94, 102, 181, 195, 199, 210, 237)
Wayne County General Hospital
(boxes 24, 94, 103-104, 127, 156, 195, 209, 237)
Affirmative Action (Compliance, Integration, Minority Programs)
(boxes 15, 77-80, 90-91, 120, 175, 198, 223, 227, 231-232, 234-235, 289, 294-295, 303, 311-312)
Animal Research (including Unit for Laboratory Animal Research)
(boxes 1, 3, 54-55, 83, 105, 170, 172, 186, 189, 191, 195, 222, 283)
Cabot, Hugh
(boxes 33-38)
Cancer Research
(boxes 2, 4, 15-16, 54, 169, 192, 224-225, 282-283, 291)
Fauri Committee
(see Hospital Study and Advisory Committee)
Flexner, Abraham
(box 33)
Furstenberg, Albert Carl
(primarily boxes 40-73)
Hospital Study and Advisory Committee
(boxes 23, 109, 170)
Inteflex Program
(boxes 106, 157, 172, 214, 228,)
MCARE
(boxes 214, 229, 255-256, 270-273, 301, 318-321)
Medical Center Review Committee
(boxes 94, 173)
Medical School Deanship Review (Willson Committee)
(box 178)
Medical Science Research Buildings (Planning and Construction)
(boxes 1-2, 15, 57, 84-85)
Medical Service Plan (Professional Fees)
(boxes 80, 96, 166-167, 174, 188-189, 199, 209, 231, 254-255, 270-273, 318-321)
Michigan Association for Regional Medical Programs (MARMP)
(boxes 26-30, 156)
Michigan Coordinating Council for Public Higher Education: Committee to Consider the Location and Sponsorship of the Expansion of Medical Education
(boxes 30-31)
Novy, Frederick George
(boxes 32-43)
Replacement Hospital Project
(boxes 81, 94, 109-112, 127, 157-160, 215)
Transplant (Policy and Research)
(boxes 3, 101, 219, 225)
Vaughn, Victor Clarence
(boxes 32-34)
University Hospital
(boxes 16-17, 19-23, 38, 45, 82, 108-112, 177, 214, 236, 297-298)
World War I
(primarily boxes 43-48)
World War II
(primarily boxes 43-48)